Eric Donohue

Ontario, CA 91764 | Phone: (323) 546-2748 | Email: ericdon10@icloud.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericdonohue | GitHub: https://github.com/edonohue8 | Portfolio: https://edonohue8.github.io/portfolio

Summary

Proficient Full Stack Web Developer & Database Administrator (DBA) with 9+ years of experience designing, coding, and testing database solutions in MySQL environment. Received Coding Bootcamp certificate. Seeking to use proven database administrator skills to develop and improve professional websites. Able to maintain good relationships with co-workers, clients and managers utilizing Emotional Intelligence. Self-starter/multi-tasker with attention to detail.

Technical Skills

Browser Based Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Local/Session

Storage and IndexedDB, React.js

Other languages: C#

API Interaction: API, JSON, AJAX

Deployment/Command-Line Fundamentals: Heroku, Git, Github pages

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Server Side Development: Node.js, Express, User Authentication, PWAs, MERN Stack **Quality Assurance**: Unit Testing, Functional Testing, Linting, Continuous Integration

Misc: Proven ability to learn new technologies and use that knowledge effectively | Knowledge of Agile Scrum

Methodology | Knowledge of Software Development Life Cycle and DevOps | Typing speed of 95 WPM

Projects

Chitter Chatter | https://github.com/bbrintle/chitter-chatter | https://chitterchatter-app-ed.herokuapp.com

- Chitter Chatter is a morale booster/community builder app. The purpose of this application is to help put productivity back in the workplace.
- Core responsibilities include coding in the back-end of the MERN app, researching and implementing middleware, and working on styling components in the front-end of the application
- Built with ReactJS, Node and Express Web Server, MongoDB Atlas, routes (GET, POST, etc.), Heroku deployment, Passport user authentication, Pusher

Freebeez | https://github.com/edonohue8/Freebeez | https://project2-group5.herokuapp.com

- Freebeez is a web app to post and claim free items, letting users post items while building a network connecting the item poster with interested parties, with a fun bee theme.
- Core responsibilities include setting up the template engine (i.e. Handlebars.js), working on the database integration, and deploying the application on Heroku.
- Built with HTML, CSS (framework Bootstrap), JavaScript (including jQuery), Node.js and Express, Handlebars.js (template engine), MySQL with Sequelize ORM, and Heroku (deployment)

International Travel Decision Assistant | https://github.com/edonohue8/int-travel-asst | https://edonohue8.github.io/int-travel-asst

- An application for airline travelers to access travel advisory information, flight quotes, and news.
- Core responsibilities include using jQuery to code the date-picker, compiling the origin and destination location drop-downs, and connecting the application to different APIs for information.
- Built with HTML, CSS/Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery

Work Day Planner | https://github.com/edonohue8/work-day-planner | https://edonohue8.github.io/work-day-planner | <a href="

Word Day Planner is a calendar application to be productive.

- Core responsibilities include utilizing Bootstrap's grid system, coding JavaScript to make sure planner functions, and adding styling.
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Experience

Database Administrator / Development Associate (remote)

Beit T'Shuvah / Culver City, CA / October 2018 to present

- Optimize database by analyzing tables, the records per table, and the number of indexes per table
- Respond to database issues and inform management. Follow through and establish permanent fixes
- Help colleagues' comprehension of database systems by conducting individual training sessions and creating user-friendly training materials

Key Accomplishments:

- Support team of 20+ team members resolving database issues and requests
- Consistently accommodate 35 tickets per week

Data and Campaign Services Coordinator

Crossroads School for Arts & Sciences / Santa Monica, CA / September 2017 – October 2018

- Updated website debugging cross-browser compatibility issues
- Utilized web analytic tools to determine qualitative and quantitative data from website and improve online experience for visitors
- Assisted Development team with "best practice" database design/development
- Managed the performance, integrity and security of donor and constituent databases and related management information systems
- Troubleshooted database/application bugs/issues

Key Accomplishments:

- Conducted refresher database training for team of 7 colleagues, every 3 months
- Consistently accommodated 30 tickets per week

Field Technician

Bicycle Transit Systems / Pasadena, CA / June 2017 – September 2017

- Worked with software engineers to plan and develop improved testing protocols
- Collaborated with colleagues to ideate data-driven solutions for users, prioritizing based on business impact; customer focused
- On-site servicing, diagnostics, and repairs for electrical products/equipment

Key Accomplishments:

- Resolved 10+ incident reports per week
- Worked with IT and software engineers to set up meetings every 2 weeks

Program Assistant

SEIU-UHW West & Joint Employer Education Fund / Los Angeles, CA / Sep 2007 – Feb 2017

- Changed look and feel of current system using MySQL
- Created models for new database development and updates to existing ones
- Created and maintained system documentation and workflow materials for database application and processes
- Worked side-by-side with designers and product owners to create new features, test ideas, and pushed live changes that impacted a large user base
- Worked with Team and troubleshooted performance issues

Key Accomplishments:

- Processed over 40 SQL statements successfully per month
- Supported 50+ users in the organization resolving database issues and requests

Education

Certificate, Coding Bootcamp / Full Stack Flex Program: UCR Extension / Riverside, CA 2020 – 2021, A+

Computer Science applied to JavaScript (i.e. Data Structures), Browser Based Technologies (i.e. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Local/Session Storage and IndexedDB, React.js), API Interaction (i.e. API, JSON, AJAX), Deployment/Command-Line Fundamentals (i.e. Heroku, Git, Github pages), C#, Databases (i.e. MySQL, MongoDB), Server Side Development (i.e. Node.js, Express, User Authentication, PWAs, MERN Stack), Quality Assurance (i.e. Unit Testing, Functional Testing, Linting, Continuous Integration)

Bachelor of Science – BS, Business Administration: California Coast University / Santa Ana, CA 2015 – 2019, Graduated Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.73